Seyma Kalay
Via Caniana, 2
Bergamo, Lombardia 24126

(338) 962 8589

✓ seymakalay@hotmail.com

✓ eymakalay

✓ seymakalay

HR Department January 9, 2022

Dear Mr/Mrs,

Through this letter, I would like to introduce myself and express my interest for the opening position at your company.

I am currently a Ph.D. student -waiting for the thesis defense, which will take place in early 2022- enrolled in Applied Economics and Management (AEM) at the University of Bergamo. During my studies, I have gained solid practical experience in data manipulation, analysis, visualization, mapping, implementing machine learning (both supervised & unsupervised) algorithms, and building interactive user-faces. In addition, I have theoretical background to do web scraping, text-mining, and network analysis. Thus, I am keen to continue my career in the business sector, under the relevant topics.

I have enclosed my resume and I look forward to hearing from you for an interview opportunity in the near future. For further information, please do not hesitate to contact me, preferably via email.

Sincerely,

Seyma Kalay

Attached: curriculum vitæ

Seyma Kalay

Curriculum Vitae

Via Caniana, 2
Bergamo, Lombardia 24126

⑤ (338) 962 8589

☑ seymakalay@hotmail.com
⑥ ~seyma.kalay
⑤ seymakalay



Education

2017-Present Doctor of Philosophy in Applied Economics and Management,

Department of Economics and Management, University of Bergamo (Italy).

(Expected graduate by February 2022)

2013 - 2016 Master of Science in Finance,

Department of Economics and Statistics, University of Siena (Italy).

2011 - 2012 Certificate in Masters of Business Administration Program,

College of Business, University of Auburn (USA).

2016 - 2010 Bachelor of Science in Astronomy and Space Science,

Department of Science, University of Istanbul (Turkey).

Doctoral Dissertation

Title Access to Credit, Using Machine Learning Techniques.

Supervisors Prof. Michela Cameletti, Prof. Federica Maria Orgio

Description Applying machine learning techniques to find out the probability of credit default and implementing

web applications.

Master Thesis

Title Optimal Portfolio Weights Using Markowitz Portfolio Theory.

Supervisors Prof. Claudio Pacati

Description Finding the optimal stock portfolio weights, using both covariance and shrinkage covariance matrix.

Experiences

2017-Present Researcher - Statistics,

Department of Economics and Management, University of Bergamo (Italy),

Applying machine learning technique to find out the probability of credit default and implementing web applications.

2016 Internship - Portfolio,

Ziraat Portfolio, Istanbul (Turkey),

Observed equity and bond market, familiar with behavioral finance, created a statistical model to maximize the portfolio's return and proved the model efficiency by tracking the data.

2015 Internship - Portfolio,

Invest-AZ, Istanbul (Turkey),

To analyze the companies by looking at their income statements and balance sheets to make sure it is beneficial to invest in those companies.

2012 Internship - Accounted,

Varkan Group, Istanbul (Turkey),

Have been effectively responsible for recording accounting cycle and kept tracking consistent balances on both suppliers and purchasers on the company's system.

2007–2010 Part time - Real Estate,

Emlak Ada, Istanbul (Turkey),

Was actively involved in the marketing and communications of the firm. Drafted contracts, scheduled meetings, handled negotiations, updated company website, collaborated with other real estate agencies, generated new solutions, and conducted research on customer needs and preferences.

Skills and Competencies

Languages: Native in Turkish, advance in English, intermediate in Italian, beginner in Spanish.

Computer: Competitive in: Latex, Microsoft Office, R, Shiny Application. New in: Html, Python, SQL.

Strengths: Creative, analytic thinker, problem solver, good at teamwork, interpersonal skills, determined, disciplined, accountable, highly motivated, responsible, strong work ethics, positive mindset, adaptable, rapid learning capability.

Software

- **R** Package Pomodoro CRAN: Comparison of predictive power models. This package is intended to make modeling and comparing the predictive powers easier based on the data-splits and all data set.
- R Package Pepe CRAN: Is intended to make descriptive statistics easier, expected release late 2022.

Awards and Honors

2017-Present UNIBG PhD Fund,

2013-2016 DSU - Toscana,

2007–2010 Turkish Gas Foundation Scholarship,

2007–2010 Turkish Women Community Scholarship,

2006–2010 Yapi Kredi Bank Scholarship.

References

Asst. Prof.: Daniel Felix Ahelegbey; University of Pavia; Assistant Professor; dfkahey@hotmail.com

Prof.: Zikri Altun; University of Marmara; Head of the department of Physic; zikalt@marmara.edu.tr

Prof.: Claudio Pacati; University of Siena; Department of Economics and Statistics; claudio.pacati@unisi.it